School of Mathematical Sciences, Queensland University of Technology



■ james.hogg@hdr.qut.edu.au | ② JamieHogg-depo | ⑤ jamieahogg | У JamieAHogg

I am a current PhD student in the School of Mathematical Sciences at the Queensland University of Technology (QUT) under the supervision of Distinguished Professor Kerrie Mengersen, Dr Susanna Cramb, Professor Peter Baade and Dr Jessica Cameron. My PhD work is funded by the internationally-awarded Australian Cancer Atlas, where my role is to develop Bayesian methodology to generate small area level cancer risk factor estimates. I am passionate about accessible research, Bayesian inference, and spatial modelling, and am dedicated to making a positive impact in the field of cancer research.

Research interests

R, tidyverse, Stan Spatio/hierarchical modelling Bayesian inference Spatial variation in cancer outcomes Visualisations/mapping

Education and qualifications

Bachelor of Music with Distinction

Brisbane, Australia

QUEENSLAND UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (QUT) • Minor in statistics (4 units)

- GPA: 6.5
- Dean's Award for Excellence (all 6 semesters)

Master of Biostatistics

UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND (UQ)

Virtual 2018-2020

- Provided by the Biostatistics Colloboration of Australia
- Dean's Commendation for Academic Excellence (2018 & 2019)
- Thesis complete at Cancer Council Queensland

Doctor of Philosophy, Statistics

Brisbane, Australia

QUEENSLAND UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (QUT)

2021 (ongoing)

• PhD funded by the internationally-awarded Australian Cancer Atlas

Graduate Statistician (Gstat) Accreditation

STATISTICAL SOCIETY OF AUSTRALIA 2021 (ongoing)

Experience

Marking (casual) Virtual

UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND (UQ)

July 2021 - October 2022

- Course title: Categorical Data and Generalised Linear Models (STAT7608)
- Course title: Regression Modelling 2 (STAT7619)
- Course title: Applied Regression Analyses (PUBH7631)

Tutor (casual) Brisbane, Australia

QUEENSLAND UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (QUT)

September - November 2021

• Course title: Quantitative Skills for Health Scientists (LQB286)

Research assistant (part-time)

Brisbane, Australia

QUEENSLAND UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (QUT)

October 2021 - March 2022

• Project: Modifiable areal unit problem (MAUP) in disease mapping • Co-investigators: Dr Susanna Cramb, Ass. Prof. Helen Thompson

Organiser and host Virtual

STANCONNECT 2022: STAN THROUGH SPACE AND TIME July - November 2022 Internship (full-time) Virtual

DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH, WESTERN AUSTRALIA (DOHWA)

August - November 2022

- · Project: Bayesian modelling
- Supervisors: Dr Susanna Cramb, Dr Alex Xiao
- · Recommended spatio-temporal models for a wide range of health data
- Provided lengthy and detailed reports giving the details of spatio-temporal models
- Created detailed and large R code scrips to run a variety of models
- · Created training materials for 3-days of intensive Bayesian spatio-temporal course

Co-chair of Bayesian Research and Applications (BRAG) group

QUEENSLAND UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (QUT)

· Organiser of fortnightly internal talks on Bayesian research

Instructor/presentor of Bayesian training

DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH, WESTERN AUSTRALIA (DOHWA)

• Three days of intensive training on Bayesian spatial temporal analysis

Research assistant (part-time)

Virtual
November 2022 (ongoing)

Brisbane, Australia

June 2022 (ongoing)

Perth, Australia

November 2022

DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH, WESTERN AUSTRALIA (DOHWA)

· Consulting on bayesian modelling

Selected research presentations.

Short talk

Moreton Island, Australia

ACEMS Final Retreat

November 2021

• Title: Modelling cancer risk factors in Australia

Contributed talk Virtual

SMALL AREA ESTIMATION, SURVEYS AND DATA SCIENCE

• Title: Searching for stability: Introducing a method of small area estimation for proportions using severely sparse data

Short talk QUT, Brisbane, Australia

QANZIAM CONFERENCE June 2022

• Title: Searching for stability in Bayesian small area estimation of proportions

Poster presentation Montreal, Canada

THE BAYESIAN YOUNG STATISTICIANS MEETING

June 2022

May 2022

June 2022

September 2022

November 2022

Virtual

• Title: Introducing a Bayesian two-stage logistic-normal model for small area estimation of proportions

Poster presentationMontreal, Canada

International Society of Bayesian Analysis (ISBA) World Meeting

• Title: Introducing a Bayesian two-stage logistic-normal model for small area estimation of proportions

Poster presentation QUT, Brisbane, Australia

CENTRE FOR DATA SCIENCE SHOWCASE

Title: Searching for stability in Bayesian small area estimation of proportions

Short talk Virtual

SECOND EARLY CAREER RESEARCHER CANCER EPIDEMIOLOGY CONFERENCE

• Title: Risk factors and the Australian Cancer Atlas: the trepidation of instability and sparsity in small area estimation

SPARSE SYMPOSIUM

November 2022

• Title: Risk factors and the Australian Cancer Atlas: the trepidation of instability and sparsity in small area estimation

Invited talk Virtual

EPIDEMIOLOGY IN GOVERNMENT (EIG) SPECIAL INTEREST GROUP (SIG) MEETING

December 2022

• Title: Mapping Cancer: The Australian Cancer Atlas

Awards

Short talk

Star Graduate

MASTERS OF BIOSTATISTICS

December 2022

JANUARY 2023 JAMES HOGG · CURRICULUM VITAE

Honourable Mention for Best Student Presentation

OANZIAM CONFERENCE June 2022

Best Oral Presentation Award

SECOND EARLY CAREER RESEARCHER CANCER EPIDEMIOLOGY CONFERENCE

November 2022

Professional memberships

Statistical Society of Australia (SSA) International Society of Bayesian Analysis (ISBA) Centre for Data Science (CDS) Health Equity Research with Outcomes (HERO)

Software

R, Stata, Python MS Office Suite, Latex, Endnote, Mendeley Git Bash Stan, WinBUGS, JAGS

Referees _____

Doctor Jessica Cameron

RESEARCH FELLOW-SPATIAL MODELLING, DESCRIPTIVE EPIDEMIOLOGY

• Email: JessicaCameron@cancerqld.org.au

• Phone: +61 7 3634 5387

Professor Peter Baade

SENIOR MANAGER, DESCRIPTIVE EPIDEMIOLOGY

• Email: PeterBaade@cancerqld.org.au

• Phone: +61 7 3634 5317

Doctor Michael Waller

BCA Program Coordinator, Senior Lecturer

• Email: m.waller@ug.edu.au

• Phone: +61 7 3365 5552

Cancer Council Queensland

Cancer Council Queensland

University of Queensland